mbs.ac.uk 2019-12-14

# Privacy | Alliance MBS

Hello we are Alliance Manchester Business School, part of The University of Manchester - you may also know us as Alliance MBS.

At Alliance MBS we're committed to protecting your privacy so we make sure we protect any personal information you give us.

We respect all personal data you choose to share with us, including that which we may obtain from other sources, and we will ensure it is stored safely and processed fairly and lawfully in accordance with the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulation (May 2018).

This page, together with our cookies policy and Frequently Asked Questions below, will let you know exactly how we use and protect your personal information.

Alliance MBS is part of The University of Manchester and for purposes of data protection law the University is the data controller. You can read more about the University's approach to data protection [here](http://www.manchester.ac.uk/privacy/).

If you have any questions about this please contact us \- we're happy to help. 

## Questions

Below we have answered a range of questions to help you better understand how we protect your personal information:

###  What information do we collect?

Personal information is any information that can be used to identify you.

So, for example, if you communicate with our programme teams or attend one of our events, we may collect and process the personal information that you’ve provided.

This personal information may include your name, email address, postal address, telephone or mobile number and date of birth; biographical or professional background; as well as how you came to find us or about our services or events.

We may also collect details of your visits to our website, for example your location data, other sites you’ve visited and the resources that you access. We use this to provide you with the information, services or products that are most relevant to you.

To understand how we use information about the communications devices you use, such as IP address (the location of device on the internet) and cookies, please see our cookie policy page.

###  Keeping your information up-to-date

To make sure we always have the most up-to-date information about how to contact you we may also, from time to time, update your records to reflect any changes to your personal information.

This information may come directly from you, or it may come from a third party that we consider is legitimate and trustworthy and in circumstances where it is appropriate and where you will have had a clear expectation that your details would be passed on for this purpose.

###  How we use cookies

We use cookies to give you a more personalised experience online and by continuing to use our site, you agree to our use of cookies. 

Cookies help us create a more effective website that reflects your needs.

We may also collect and record information about how you use our site by collecting your IP address (the number that identifies a specific computer or other internet device).

Cookie files and IP addresses will never identify you as an individual.

For more information on cookie files and IP addresses read our cookie policy. This page also includes instructions on how to disable cookies if you don’t want them to be used.

###  How will we contact you?

Our aim is to make sure any communication you receive from us helps you get the most from your relationship with Alliance MBS.

We love to keep you posted with news about our research and programmes; alongside the variety of exciting ways you can work with us in the future. This can relate to all communications with you from Alliance MBS or to certain campaigns or channels of communication.  Before you decide to study or work with Alliance MBS we will ask if you want to opt-in to receiving these communications, for example when you download a brochure or make an enquiry using our website

If you are a prospective student, this may include details about scholarship opportunities, taster sessions or webinars to help you complete your application in the best way.

We will not contact you again if you ask us not to and you can change your contact preferences by using the link which is at the bottom of all of our emails and newsletters.

###  Event attendees

By registering for an Alliance MBS event such as our Vital Topics lectures, Teddy Chester and Grigor McClelland lectures and taster events; we will process your data in accordance with our legitimate interests.

We may collect the following types of information:

  * Name and title
  * Contact details
  * Feedback on the event

This information will be provided by you, and we will use your information to communicate with you about the event and relevant future events. We may ask you to complete surveys before and after the event, to improve the format of our events.

However, you will be given the opportunity to opt-out of receiving information about future events and we will not contact you again if you ask us not to.

You can change your contact preferences by using the link which is at the bottom of all of our event communications or by emailing [events@manchester.ac.uk](mailto:events@manchester.ac.uk).

###  How will we handle your information and with other organisations?

We will not rent or sell your personal information to other organisations for use by them in any way, including in their own direct marketing activities.

If you make a booking for our Crowne Plaza hotel or Staybridge Suites via the Alliance MBS website, in order to complete the booking we will send them your details in a secure way. Please see Crowne Plaza and Staybridge Suites privacy policy [here](https://www.ihg.com/content/gb/en/customer-care/privacy_statement).

Where you have given us permission to contact you, we may pass on your information to external service providers to contact you on our behalf. For example, when we conduct market research to get your views to find out what we could do better. We will always let you know in advance before we do this.

We may ask external service providers to carry out website tracking and analysis on our behalf as described in the cookies policy. For instance, we may pass on anonymised digital data (such as cookie files and IP addresses) to our media agency Mediacom to monitor how well our campaigns are performing. These files will never identify you as an individual.

###  Links to third party websites

This website may include links to other websites, not owned or managed by Alliance MBS. Whilst we only link to reputable websites, we cannot be held responsible for the privacy of data collected by sites not managed by Alliance MBS, nor can we accept responsibility or liability for those policies. For this reason you should consult the privacy policy on any external website you link to before you submit any data to those websites.

###  Your rights

If you wish to exercise any of your rights, as listed below, please write to The University of Manchester's Information Governance Office:

Information Governance Office  
University of Manchester   
Oxford Road  
Manchester   
M13 9PL   
UK

a. Access to your personal information;  
b. Objection to processing of your personal information;  
c. Objection to automated decision-making and profiling;  
d. Restriction of processing of your personal information;  
e. Your personal data portability;  
f.  Rectification of your personal information; and   
g. Erasure of your personal information.

If you make a request relating to any of the rights listed above, we will consider each request in accordance with all applicable data protection laws and regulations.
